

Chandra Mouli

UI/UX Designer

Blk-657, Woodlands Ring Road #06-324, Singapore-730657

CONTACT DETAILS

HP: +65 - 8818 3200

Email ID: gpmouli@gmail.com

Portfolio: gpmouli.com

Fin: G0588750Q

Professional Skills

Web Design

Photoshop

Wordpress

Bootstrap

UI Design

HTML5

CSS3

Javascript

Ajax

jQuery

AngularJs

FRAMEWORKS

PHP

CodeIgniter

Python

Django

Web2py

DATABASES

SQL

MYSQL

Senior-Lead Designer / Front-End Web Developer / UI-UX Designer

Professional **Web** and **Mobile UI/UX** designer and developer with 9 years of experience. Using the latest web technologies; specializing in developing clean, complex, intuitive cross-browser / Multi-device web interfaces with subtle and complementary animations and visual effects.

Creative and highly skilled professional hands-on front-end developer with a superb track record of managing *multiple complex design and development projects in various environments*. Able to manage stakeholder expectations and willing to take full responsibility for the delivering of project objectives. Creating visual design, animation and effects that are unique and trend setting in the market.

Chandra is an easy going individual who enjoys new challenges and developing his skills with the latest technology. He has a holistic understanding of internet technologies from design, development and search engine optimization requirements and he creates value to the overall go-to market objectives.

Work Experience

Cynopsis-Solutions Pte Ltd (Singapore)

UI / UX Front-End Web Developer

20-05-2015 - Present (7 Months)

As part of a medium development team, I have primarily been responsible for the development of new Python projects using Django open source framework, Codelgniter, as well as maintaining a number of legacy Web2py websites for our clients.

The biggest project was Artemis, iRis an Anti Money Laundering site with approximately 72 modules. I led the development effort in migrating our older Java-based websites to Python and Django with more interactive for clients, as well as maintaining a web2p sites. Worked with clients within Singapore.

Key Achievements:

- Developed prototype concepts using Axure, Photoshop, and Illustrator concept designs
- Integrated responsive UI designs into Django framework for web and mobile using HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery / JavaScript
- Created Artemis, iRis, a custom functionality built using Django, with jQuery AJAX, AngularJS components. Also designed from the start with SEO in mind.
- Developed Application to asses JSON and XML from Restful web service from consumer side using JavaScript and Angular.JS
- Developed the front-end web page by using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, taking advantage of the frameworks Angular. JS and Django
- Maintenanced Python/SQL (DJango) projects, Communicating and interfacing with previous developers on a regular basis.
- Made heavy use of Chrome Developer Tools + Firebug to ensure front-end code and assets were optimized and high-quality
- Used Responsive Web Design templates to meet cutting-edge technology requirements

Tools and Technologies: Adobe Photoshop, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Ajax, Jquery, AngularJS, Django, Git, Nginx, Python

UI/UX Projects Overview

UI Prototype 67+
CMS Sites 80
E-Commerce Sites 21
Portals 119+
Flash Sites 15
Other Projects 20+

Professional Skills

Web Design

Photoshop

Wordpress

Bootstrap

UI Design

HTML5

CSS3

Javascript

jQuery

AngularJs

FRAMEWORKS

PHP

Codelgniter

Python

Django

Web2py

DATABASES

SQL

MYSQL

Work Experience

Dot Spiders Pte Ltd (Singapore)

Senior-Lead Designer / Front-End Web Developer

Jan 2013 - March 2015 (2year 2months)

Responsible for the front-end design and development of all projects over the span of almost 2 years. Hired as the first lead web designer in the firm, *handled multiple design projects simultaneously of CMS*, *e-commerce and web portals*. Designed and developed a wide array of theatrical creative assets using the latest web technologies. Handled client expectations and delivery protocol with company process and documentation flow.

Worked with clients within Singapore and internationally.

Key Achievements:

- Worked on multiple projects and successfully delivered 87 projects in a span of 1 year and 7 months
- * Expert in create Sitemaps, Flow Diagrams, Wireframes, project Doc.
- Introduced new features to the sites, including JS/CSS animations, responsive design and HTML5
- Ensured all projects were full responsive designs according to both Android and Apple latest device and software upgrades.
- Expertise in HTML5, CSS3, Ajax, jQuery, user experience, responsive web design, iOS app design, logo and icon design, website template design, branding
- Highly experienced in prototypes, web templates, testing and developing responsive sites for multi device use, on Android and iOS platforms.
- Developed, enhanced and maintained scalable front-end architectures for enterprise level sites using OOP CSS, JSON, Datasource

Project Types: CMS, E-Commerce, Portals, CRM, Fund Manager portals.

Tech.: Photoshop, Illustrator, JSP, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Pycharm, Axure, Hotgloo, Flash Main Clients: UOB, DBS, Tan Tock Seng, Sage, Honda, Castrol, Mount Faber, Litaflex..etc.

Enggsol Pte Ltd (Singapore)

Lead Designer/UI&UX Developer

August 2010 - December 2012 (2year 4months)

Hands-on Lead Web designer and front-end developer; executed all stages of website and software product design, from research and requirements gathering, storyboarding, interaction design, production and usability testing. Involved in taking the creative brief and understanding the client requirements and brand image. Conceptualized, created design mock-ups, wireframes, obtaining the approval followed by front-end coding.

The role evolved from a lead designer role to project coordination for the backend team totaling 25 members.

Other Skills

3DS Max

Maya

After Effects

Flash

Adobe Premiere

Video Editing Softwares

Professional Skills

Web Design

Photoshop

Wordpress

Bootstrap

UI Design

HTML5

CSS3

Javascript

¡Query

AngularJs

FRAMEWORKS

PHP

CodeIgniter

Python

Django

Web2py

DATABASES

SQL

MYSQL

Key Achievements:

- Expert in create Sitemaps, Flow Diagrams, Wireframes, project Doc.
- Pioneer lead designer in the firm, Expert at hands-on coding clean HTML and advanced CSS to Web standards.
- Researched and implemented new methods, tools, and technologies to aid frontend development
- Developing best practices and processes in the areas of design and HTML/CSS, JSP, Jquery, Ajax, JSON, Datasource
- Transitioning the company from tabular layouts to CSS Layouts
- Assisted in the operational set-up of the Philippines office (onsite) and trained the team in Singapore Website design and themes.

Project Types: CMS, E-Commerce, Portals, Custom Applications
Tools: Photoshop, Illustrator, JSP, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Pencil Drawing, Flash
Main Clients: HDB, Tan Tock Seng, SJDA, Sage, Showy, ADDP, Vitamin
Science,...etc.

Infar International Pte Ltd (Singapore)

Web Designer

June 2008 - July 2010 (2year 1month)

Creative and strategic problem solving to help interpret stakeholder's goals and help outline the project's business requirements. Primary UX objective is to reach as many people as possible through in-depth usability research and simple information architecture.

Key Achievements:

- Worked closely with multi-disciplinary teams to establish best practices for responsive UI design mock-ups with three breakpoints to accommodate a variety of mobile screen resolutions.
- New design development wire framing, visual design, html/CSS mock ups and Web site UI implementation including .JSP, CSS, JQuery and JavaScript components, i.e. Data grids, modal windows, tab navigation, etc.
- Established a linear layout that works for every screen and is appropriate for the particular concept, minimizing the need for different layouts and extended workloads.

Languages

English

Hindi

Teluqu

Professional Skills

Web Design

Photoshop

Wordpress

Bootstrap

UI Design

HTML5

CSS3

Javascript

¡Query

AngularJs

FRAMEWORKS

PHP

Codelgniter

Python

Django

Web2py

DATABASES

SQL

MYSQL

K-soft Information Technologies INC (India)

3D Animator

November 2006 - February 2007 (4Months)

Creating drawings and make models for engineer products and animation within the team.

Key Achievements:

- Create 2D drawings and 3D drawings
- ❖ 3D texturing for products
- Lighting and Rendering
- ❖ 3D Models all engineering products and Animation

Nihar Global Info Ltd (India)

3D Animator

March 2004 - November 2006 (2year 7months)

Responsible for 3D Modelling and Animation

Key Achievements:

- Create 3D models as per the client requirements
- Photography of all the engineering products
- Texturing and Animation
- V-Ray Rendering

EDUCATION

Informatics Group (Singapore)

Advanced Diploma Gaming and Animation *Year of Passing*: 2008

Bachelors Degree (India)

Bachelor of Commerce *Year of Passing: 2006*

Arena Multimedia (India)

Advanced Diploma in Multimedia

Year of Passing: 2002

AWARDS

Arena Multimedia

Best 3D Animator in ARENA 5th Anniversary from HYDERABAD - India